The storm came on slowly one afternoon.
一天下午，风暴缓缓来临。
The clouds looked as if they were stumbling along before the wind, frightened.
云朵看上去像是被风推着，跌跌撞撞地往前走，一副惊恐的样子。
The sea took its cue.
大海也闻风而动。
It started rising and falling in a manner that made my heart sink.
海面开始起伏，那架势让我的心直往下沉。
I took in the net.
我把网收了回来。
Oh, you should have seen that landscape!
啊，你真该看看那番景象！
What I had seen up till now were mere hillocks of water.
在此之前，我见过的都只不过是些小水丘。
These swells were truly mountains.
这些涌浪，真真正正是一座座大山。
The valleys we found ourselves in were so deep they were gloomy.
我们身陷的浪谷那么深，深得一片昏暗。
Their sides were so steep the lifeboat started sliding down them, nearly surfing.
浪谷两侧的坡那么陡，救生艇开始顺坡下滑，几乎是在冲浪了。
The raft was getting exceptionally rough treatment, being pulled out of the water and dragged along bouncing.
木筏被折腾得格外厉害：被拽出水面，一路蹦跳着被拖行。
I deployed both sea anchors fully, at different lengths so that they would not interfere with each other.
我把两只海锚都完全放了出去，绳长各不相同，这样它们就不会相互干扰。
Climbing the giant swells, the boat clung to the sea anchors like a mountain climber to a rope.
小艇往巨大的涌浪上爬时，紧紧拽着海锚，就像登山者紧抓着绳索。
We would rush up until we reached a snow-white crest in a burst of light and foam and a tipping forward of the lifeboat.
我们会一路往上冲，直冲到雪白的浪峰，霎时间光亮与泡沫迸发，救生艇向前一倾。
The view would be clear for miles around.
方圆数英里的景象都会一览无余。
But the mountain would shift, and the ground beneath us would start sinking in a most stomach-sickening way.
可是这座山会移动，我们身下的地面会开始下沉，沉得叫人胃里翻江倒海，恶心极了。
In no time we would be sitting once again at the bottom of a dark valley, different from the last but the same, with thousands of tons of water hovering above us and with only our flimsy lightness to save us.
转眼间，我们又会坐在一道幽暗的浪谷底部，它和上一道不同，却又一模一样；数千吨海水悬在我们头顶，能救我们的，只有我们那份单薄的轻盈。
The land would move once more, the sea-anchor ropes would snap to tautness, and the roller coaster would start again.
大地会再次移动，海锚绳会啪地绷紧，过山车又会开动起来。
The sea anchors did their job well—in fact, nearly too well.
海锚的活儿干得很好——事实上，几乎好过了头。
Every swell at its crest wanted to take us for a tumble, but the anchors, beyond the crest, heaved mightily and pulled us through, but at the expense of pulling the front of the boat down.
每一道涌浪到了浪峰处，都想让我们栽个跟头；但海锚已在浪峰另一侧，它们猛力一拽，把我们拖了过去，代价却是把船头往下拉。
The result was an explosion of foam and spray at the bow.
结果，船头处泡沫和浪花轰然炸开。
I was soaked through and through each time.
每一次我都被浇得从里到外湿个透。
Then a swell came up that was particularly intent on taking us along.
接着来了一道涌浪，格外执意要把我们卷走。
This time the bow vanished underwater.
这一次，船头消失在了水下。
I was shocked and chilled and scared witless.
我又惊又冷，吓得魂飞魄散。
I barely managed to hold on.
我勉强才抓牢，没有松手。
The boat was swamped.
小艇里灌满了水。
I heard Richard Parker roar.
我听见理查德·帕克一声咆哮。
I felt death was upon us.
我觉得我们死到临头了。
The only choice left to me was death by water or death by animal.
留给我的选择只有一个：要么死于水，要么死于兽口。
I chose death by animal.
我选择了死于兽口。
While we sank down the back of the swell, I jumped onto the tarpaulin and unrolled it towards the stern, closing in Richard Parker.
我们顺着涌浪的背坡往下落时，我跳上防水布，把它朝船尾展开，将理查德·帕克关在了里面。
If he protested, I did not hear him.
就算他抗议过，我也没有听见。
Faster than a sewing machine working a piece of cloth, I hooked down the tarpaulin on both sides of the boat.
我把小艇两侧的防水布都钩牢了，速度比缝纫机缝一块布还要快。
We were climbing again.
我们又在往上攀升了。
The boat was lurching upwards steadily.
小艇颠簸着，持续不断地向上冲。
It was hard to keep my balance.
我很难保持平衡。
The lifeboat was now covered and the tarpaulin battened down, except at my end.
此时，除了我这一头，救生艇已经盖上了，防水布也用压条固定好了。
I squeezed in between the side bench and the tarpaulin and pulled the remaining tarpaulin over my head.
我挤进侧边长凳和防水布之间，把剩下的防水布拉过来盖在头上。
I did not have much space.
我没有多少空间。
Between bench and gunnel there was twelve inches, and the side benches were only one and a half feet wide.
长凳与船舷上缘之间有十二英寸，侧边长凳只有一英尺半宽。
But I was not so foolhardy, even in the face of death, as to move onto the floor of the boat.
但即便面对死亡，我也没有鲁莽到要挪到小艇底板上去的地步。
There were four hooks left to catch.
还有四个钩子没挂上。
I slipped a hand through the opening and worked the rope.
我把一只手从开口处伸出去，摆弄着绳子。
With each hook done, it was getting harder to get the next.
每挂好一个钩子，下一个就越发难挂。
I managed two.
我好不容易挂上了两个。
Two hooks left.
还剩两个钩子。
The boat was rushing upwards in a smooth and unceasing motion.
小艇正向上猛冲，动作平稳，一刻不停。
The incline was over thirty degrees.
倾斜角度超过了三十度。
I could feel myself being pulled down towards the stern.
我能感觉到自己正被往下拽向船尾。
Twisting my hand frantically, I succeeded in catching one more hook with the rope.
我发疯似的扭动着手，总算用绳子又挂上了一个钩子。
It was the best I could do.
我也就只能做到这一步了。
This was not a job meant to be done from the inside of the lifeboat but from the outside.
这活儿本来就不是要在救生艇里面干的，而是要在外面干。
I pulled hard on the rope, something made easier by the fact that holding on to it was preventing me from sliding down the length of the boat.
我使劲拉绳子，这倒还容易些，因为抓着绳子正好能防止我顺着艇身一路滑下去。
The boat swiftly passed a forty-five-degree incline.
小艇的倾斜角度很快就超过了四十五度。
We must have been at a sixty-degree incline when we reached the summit of the swell and broke through its crest onto the other side.
我们到达涌浪顶峰、冲破浪峰翻到另一侧时，倾斜角度想必已达六十度。
The smallest portion of the swell’s supply of water crashed down on us.
这道涌浪所蓄的海水，只有极小的一部分轰然砸在了我们身上。
I felt as if I were being pummelled by a great fist.
我觉得自己仿佛正被一只巨拳反复猛击。
The lifeboat abruptly tilted forward and everything was reversed: I was now at the lower end of the lifeboat, and the water that had swamped it, with a tiger soaking in it, came my way.
救生艇猛地向前倾斜，一切都颠倒了过来：现在我处在救生艇较低的那一头，先前灌满救生艇的水朝我涌来，水里还泡着一只老虎。
I did not feel the tiger—I had no precise idea of where Richard Parker was; it was pitch-black beneath the tarpaulin—but before we reached the next valley I was half-drowned.
我没有感觉到老虎——我并不确切知道理查德·帕克在哪里；防水布下面一片漆黑——但还没等我们到达下一道浪谷，我就已经被淹得半死了。
For the rest of that day and into the night, we went up and down, up and down, up and down, until terror became monotonous and was replaced by numbness and a complete giving-up.
那天余下的时光，一直到夜里，我们升了又降，降了又升，升了又降，直至恐惧变得单调乏味，取而代之的是麻木和彻底的放弃。
I held on to the tarpaulin rope with one hand and the edge of the bow bench with the other, while my body lay flat against the side bench.
我一只手抓着防水布的绳子，另一只手抓着船头长凳的边缘，身体则平贴在侧边长凳上。
In this position—water pouring in, water pouring out—the tarpaulin beat me to a pulp, I was soaked and chilled, and I was bruised and cut by bones and turtle shells.
我就保持着这个姿势——海水涌进来，又泻出去——防水布把我抽打得体无完肤，我浑身湿透，冻得发僵，还被骨头和海龟壳撞得青一块紫一块，划出了伤口。
The noise of the storm was constant, as was Richard Parker’s snarling.
风暴的轰响一刻不停，理查德·帕克的低吼也是如此。
Sometime during the night my mind noted that the storm was over.
夜里的某个时候，我的意识察觉到，风暴已经过去了。
We were bobbing on the sea in a normal way.
我们像平常一样在海面上一起一伏。
Through a tear in the tarpaulin I glimpsed the night sky.
透过防水布上的一道裂口，我瞥见了夜空。
Starry and cloudless.
满天星斗，万里无云。
I undid the tarpaulin and lay on top of it.
我解开防水布，躺在了上面。